Guide to the Cornell University pamphlet collection, circa 1870-1918.
Cornell University pamphlet collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University pamphlet collection,circa 1870-1918.
47-1-4132
15 volumes.
Pamphlets, circulars, programs, reports, letters
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pamphlets, circulars, programs, reports, and letters on various aspects of Cornell University, including academics, buildings, events on campus, athletics, student life, alumni and alumnae.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Pamphlets, circulars, programs, reports, and letters on various aspects of Cornell University, including academics, buildings, events on campus, athletics, student life, alumni and alumnae.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- History.; Cornell University -- Sports.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University -- Buildings.
Form and Genre Terms:
Pamphlets.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Sage College circular, 1870s; 1; no. 1
- Letter from Rev. Dr. Stebbins on preaching at Cornell, in Word and Work (periodical of the American Unitarian Association), October, 1873; 1; no. 2
- "The General Card Catalogue of the Library, Cornell University", 1885; 1; no. 3
- "Exercises at the Dedication of Barnes Hall," published by Cornell University Christian Association, June 16, 1889; 1; no. 4
- "Exercises and Addresses at the Laying of the Corner Stone of the University Library Building", October 30, 1889; 1; no. 5
- Cornell University Summer School, Treasurer's report, 1892; 1; no. 6
- "List of Candidates for Fellowships and Scholarships for the Year 1894-95", May 15, 1894; 1; no. 7
- Letter from the Decennial Reunion Committee to the Class of 1886, December 20, 1895; 1; no. 8
- Letter from the Decennial Reunion Committee to the Class of 1886, February 29, 1896; 1; no. 9
- "Data for the [Class of Eighteen] Eighty-Six Class Book", [1896?]; 1; no. 10
- Letter from the Decennial Reunion Committee to the Class of 1886, June 6, 1896; 1; no. 11-12
- "Official Announcement of the American Society of Naturalists Sixteenth Annual Meeting, Ithaca, New York, December 28, 29 and 30, 1897," followed by a typewritten list of attendees [?], 1897; 1; no. 13
- "New York State Science Teachers' Association" [List of attendees to the 1897 American Society of Naturalists Annual Meeting?], 1897; 1; no. 14
- Printed letter from Cornell University President Jacob Gould Schurman to Senator Nelson W. Aldrich on excluding scientific apparatus and books from a proposed tariff, April 6, 1897; 1; no. 15
- "Competitive Designs, Alumni Hall, Cornell University", April 15, 1899; 1; no. 16
- "The Columbia-Pennsylvania-Cornell Second-Varsity Regatta", May 30, 1901; 1; no. 17
- "Athletic Subscriptions: Outline of the New Plan for This Year--Its Advantages Over the Old System", 1901; 1; no. 18
- Cornell Masque, program for a Commencement performance of The Taming of the Shrew, 1901; 1; no. 19
- H. Wade Hibbard, "Management of Men in Shops: Discipline Relations of Officers and Workmen", 1902; 1; no. 20
- The Valley Breeze (periodical), published by the Philomathean Literary Society of Raisin Valley Seminary, vol. I, no. 2, containing an article on Cornell University, April 1903; 1; no. 21
- Pamphlet on Sheldon Court, scheduled to open as a Cornell dormitory in September 1903, 1903; 1; no. 22
- "The Fine Arts: Courses in Painting Offered Under the Direction of the College of Architecture", 1903; 1; no. 23
- "An Athletic Impudence Perpetrated by a Few Foolish Fellows and Given as a Relief Expedition for Cornell Athletics," including photographs of Jack Moakley and also the Cornell Varsity Crew team of 1902, May 15, 1903; 1; no. 24
- Map of the Cornell campus, showing the new athletic field, July 15, 1903; 2; no. 1
- "Rules for the Guidance of Students", September 1903; 2; no. 2
- "College of Arts and Sciences, 1904-1905" (registration and related information), 1904; 2; no. 3
- "State of New York, No. 55, in Senate, Calendar of Bills," including (on p. 35, General Order no. 490) "An act to establish a state college of agriculture at Cornell university", [1903?]; 2; no. 4
- Science (periodical), vol. XV, no. 368, including (beginning on p. 91) an article on the College of Forestry at Cornell, January 17, 1902; 2; no. 5
- "Second Report of the Board of Directors of the Cornell Co-operative Society", May 1897; 2; no. 6
- Letter to Cornell alumni, endorsing the nomination of Robert T. Morris for Alumni Trustee, June 1, 1905; 2; no. 7
- "Essay Subjects, American Colonial History, 1902" (typewritten list), 1902; 2; no. 8
- "Report of the Committee on Educational Policy", [1904?]; 2; no. 9
- Letter from Prof. W.W. Rowlee to G.W. Harris, advocating the formation of a local Anti-Mosquito League, December 8, 1904; 2; no. 10
- Letter from Graham C. Patterson, general secretary of the Cornell University Christian Association, to A.C. White, reporting on the Association's work, February 14, 1905; 2; no. 11
- General invitation to the Annual Banquet of the Cornell Association of the Southern Tier, March 15, 1899; 2; no. 12
- "Schedule of Examinations, 1902-1903", 1902; 2; no. 13
- "Schedule of Examinations, 1903-1904", 1903; 2; no. 14
- "List of Rooms and Boarding Houses, Prepared for the Cornell Summer School, 1902" (with campus map on the back), 1902; 2; no. 15
- "An Appeal to Cornellians: Cornell Needs a New and Larger Athletic Field Upon or Near the Campus," from the Athletic Field Committee, [1901?]; 2; no. 16
- Circular from the Alumni Association of Cornell University, reporting on the fundraising campaign for the new athletic field, June 15, 1902; 2; no. 17
- "Circular of Information: Cornell University," including entrance requirements and admission information, 1904; 2; no. 17a
- "Official Souvenir Program, Second Varsity Triangular Regatta, Harvard, Syracuse, Cornell, Ithaca, New York, May 30th, 1902", 1902; 2; no. 18
- "Views in the Neighborhood of Cornell University, and Other Points Reached by Excursions in the Geography Summer School", c. 1900; 2; no. 19
- Concert programs for the Glee, Banjo and Mandolin Clubs, 1900-1901; 2; no. 20-22
- Flier advertising the Campus Tavern (south of campus, adjoining Sheldon Court) and its meal plans, c. 1900; 2; no. 23
- "Sheldon Court, Ithaca, New York", 1903; 2; no. 24
- "First and Second Annual Report of the New York Central College Association, Held at the College Buildings, McGrawville", July 4, 1849 and 1850; 3; no. 1
- The prospectus of the People's College Association, outlining its founding propositions and resolutions, 1852; 3; no. 2
- "Account of the Proceedings at the Inauguration" of Cornell University, with addresses by Ezra Cornell, Andrew Dickson White, and various faculty, 1868; 3; no. 3
- Reference handbook for the Machine Shop at Sibley College, by its director, John E. Sweet, 1875; 3; no. 4
- Sage College circular about "the Facilities for the Education of Young Ladies at Cornell University", 1879; 3; no. 5
- Andrew Dickson White's report to the trustees of Cornell University on Mr. Sage's proposal to endow a college for women, 1872; 3; no. 6
- Sage College circular about the resolution to require "all lady students" to room and board at Sage College, 1884; 3; no. 7
- General prospectus about "Sage College for Women", July-September 1884; 3; no. 8
- "Catalogue of the Graduates of Cornell University" compiled by Rev. William Dexter Wilson, D.D., L.L.D., 1883; 3; no. 9
- "What Profession Shall I Choose? and How Shall I Fit Myself for It? with a Brief Statement of Facilities Offered at the Cornell University", 1884; 3; no. 10
- Sibley College circular of facilities information by its director, Robert H. Thurston, 1885; 3; no. 11
- "Special Accommodations for Commencement Week," listing the addresses of local hosts with vacant rooms for out-of-towners, 1888; 3; no. 12
- "Roster of the Cornell University Corps of Cadets", October, 1889; 3; no. 13
- "The Final Announcement of the Woodruff Scientific Expedition Around the World, Starting October 1877, and Returning October, 1879", 1877; 4; no. 1
- Transactions of the American Microscopical Society (periodical), published by the Wenborne-Sumner Co., Vol. XVII, Eighteenth Annual Meeting, held at Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., January, 1896; 4; no. 2
- General letter in support of Board of Trustees candidate, Dr. Charles G. Wagner, of the Cornell University class of 1880 and the Superintendent of the State Hospital for the Insane at Binghamton, N.Y., April, 1895; 4; no. 3
- "General Legislation of the Faculty and Extracts from the Faculty Records," miscellaneous selections from Sept., 1868 to Oct., 1890, c. 1890; 4; no. 4
- "General Legislation of the Faculty and Extracts from the Faculty Records," from June 19, 1896 to June 4, 1897, c. 1897; 4; no. 5
- "New York Press Association Fortieth Annual Convention" at Glen Summit, PA, June 29th to July 4th, 1896, with addresses by President Schurman and other Cornell faculty, 1896; 4; no. 6
- "On an Engineering Experiment Station" by R.H. Thurston, director of Sibley College (reprinted from The Sibley Journal of Engineering), 1896; 4; no. 7
- "Washington's Farewell Address," Cornell Centennial Edition, with forewords by Cornell University President J.G. Schurman and President William McKinley, 1897; 4; no. 8
- Menu and song lyrics for the Cornell University Luncheon, held at the Gymnasium, June 17, 1897, June 17, 1897; 4; no. 9
- Pamphlet for the third series of "The American Lectures on the History of Religions" entitled "Jewish Religious Life After the Exile," by Rev. T.K. Cheyne, M.A., D.D., 1897; 4; no. 10
- Member list of "The Kipling Club," with member addresses and club papers (on Rudyard Kipling), for the 1897-98 academic year, 1897; 4; no. 11
- "The Second Annual Edition of the Lakeside Magazine, published for the benefit of the Cornell University Students' Ward in the Ithaca City Hospital", 1897; 4; no. 12
- Letter (by Willard Fiske) regarding and a bibliography of "The May Collection," Reverend Samuel Joseph May's collection of slavery and anti-slavery books and pamphlets, 1871; 5; no. 1
- Architectural "style index" with numerous abbreviations to cite examples, published by the Department of Architecture, Cornell University, c. Late 1800s; 5; no. 2
- "Catalogue of Lantern Slides," manufactured at the Photographic Laboratory, Cornell University, 1875; 5; no. 3
- Cornell University's "Department of Anglo-Saxon and English Literature" curriculum and examination papers for a four-year enrollment, c. Late 1800s; 5; no. 4
- Leaflet on "Sundry Feeding Rations," prepared by the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, c. Late 1800s; 5; no. 5
- Report on the "Committee on Salaries and Reorganization of Departments" with resolutions by the Board of Trustees, 1885; 5; no. 6
- Report on the "Reorganization of the Department of History and Political Science" with resolutions by the Board of Trustees; also, a letter by Ex-President White on gifting his library of works on history and political science to Cornell University, 1887; 5; no. 7
- An address delivered by R.H. Thurston, director of Sibley Hall, on the unveiling of a bust of Hiram Sibley, June 15, 1892, 1892; 5; no. 8
- The inaugural address of President Jacob Gould Schurman, November 11th, 1892, entitled, "Grounds of an Appeal to the State for Aid to Cornell University", 1892; 5; no. 9
- "The Dedication [and proceedings and addresses] of Boardman Hall and the Presentation of the Moak Law Library," on February 14, 1893, 1893; 5; no. 10
- The University Library (periodical), vol. X, no. 3, including the article, "A Remarkable Law School," by W.G. Eliot, 5; no. 11
- "The Significance of the B.A. and Ph.B. Degrees," with the prescribed number of hours for elective studies by academic year, intended for faculty, 1895; 5; no. 12
- "Circular of Information Regarding Graduate Work," with regulations on graduate work admissions and examinations, intended for faculty, 1895; 5; no. 13
- The Kappa Alpha Theta (periodical), vol. IX, no. 3, a quarterly published by the Kappa Alpha Theta fraternity and edited by Lambda Chapter, University of Vermont, April, 1895; 5; no. 14
- "The Receipt of Custom," a sermon, preached before faculty and students of Cornell University on October 18th, 1896, Rt. Rev. G. Mott Williams, D.D., Bishop of Marquette, Class of 1879, 1896; 5; no. 15
- The prayers and hymns of the "Baccalaureate Services at the Thirtieth Commencement of Cornell University," Sunday, June 12, 1898, 1898; 5; no. 16
- Schedule for the Tenth Session of the Association of American Anatomists, held at Cornell University from December 28th to the 30th, 1897, December, 1897; 5; no. 17
- "The Powers and Duties of the Executive Department," an address delivered to Cornell University by William J. Youngs, the Secretary to the Governor, c. Late 1800s; 5; no. 18
- The "Cornell University Club" book, with a copy of its constitution and a list of its committees and members (as of 1898), 1898; 5; no. 19
- Menu and song lyrics for the Cornell University Luncheon, held at the Gymnasium, June 16, 1898, 1898; 5; no. 20
- The addresses of the opening of the Cornell Medical College by J.G. Schurman, President of Cornell University, and W.M. Polk, M.D., Dean of the Faculty of Medicine, 1898; 5; no. 21
- Pamphlet for the fourth series of "The American Lectures on the History of Religions" entitled "The Religion of Israel from the Earliest Times to the Exile," by K. Budde, D.D., 1898-1899; 5; no. 22
- "Syllabus of Lectures on the Diplomatic History of the United States from 1775 to 1800" by Hon. John W. Foster, LL.D., May, 1899; 5; no. 23
- The "Red Book" for the "Cornell Alumni Association of Buffalo" with its constitution and a list of its members (as of 1899), 1899; 5; no. 24
- The "Red Book" for the "Cornell Alumni Association of Buffalo" with its constitution and a list of its members (as of 1900-1901), 1900-1901; 5; no. 25
- "By-Laws of the Athletic Association of Cornell University" with a list of the athletic council members by sport (as of 1894), October, 1894; 5; no. 26
- Menu and distinguished toasts of the "XXXth Annual Initiation Banquet Cornell University Delta Upsilon" on November 17, 1899, 1899; 5; no. 27
- A report of a visit to the universities in the United States and Canada (including Cornell University) by the University of Birmingham, December, 1899; 5; no. 28
- The Alpha Phi Quarterly (periodical), vol. XII, no. 2, published by Alpha Chapter, Syracuse University, February, 1900; 6; no. 1
- Information pamphlet addressed to the alumni of Cornell University by the Alumni Advisory Committee of the Cornell University Christian Association, c. 1890s; 6; no. 2
- List of rules regarding public student organizations by the Committee for 1900-1901 on Student Organizations in accordance with the University Faculty, 1900-1901; 6; no. 3
- Information pamphlet for the Cornell University Christian Association, reprinted from the Cornell Alumni News of January 24, 1900, 1900; 6; no. 4
- Pamphlet about where to buy goods furnished by and to find discounts offered by the Cornell Cooperative Society (as of 1900-1901), 1900-1901; 6; no. 5
- "Constitution of the Cornell Union" with a list of the senior officers and members from the faculty, 1900; 6; no. 6
- "Cornell Legal Directory" with the addresses and commencement year of Cornell attorneys, compiled by E.P. Allen, Counsellor at Law, Rochester, N.Y., January, 1901; 6; no. 7
- The third edition of the "Cornell Legal Directory" with the addresses and commencement years of Cornell attorneys, compiled by E.P. Allen, Counsellor at Law, Rochester, N.Y., March, 1903; 6; no. 8
- "Constitution of the Cornell Co-operative Society", 1901; 6; no. 9
- "Engineering as a Profession," a Founder's Day address by William Barclay Parsons, reprinted from the Cornell Alumni News, January, 1901; 6; no. 10
- "Engineering as a Profession," a Founder's Day address by William Barclay Parsons, January, 1901; 6; no. 11
- "Address on Legal Education," delivered by Hon. Francis Miles Finch, President of the New York State Bar Association and Dean of the Faculty of Law at Cornell University, March, 1901; 6; no. 12
- "Marshall Day Address," in honor of Chief Justice John Marshall, delivered by Judge Francis Miles Finch, February, 1901; 6; no. 13
- Invitation and program for the "Fourth Annual Meeting of the New York State Household Economic Association," held at Barnes Hall, Cornell University, on May 31st, 1901, May, 1901; 6; no. 14
- "Scientific Doubts and Other Student Religious Difficulties," printed from an informal talk at Barnes Hall by Rev. Dr. Lyman Abbott, October, 1901; 6; no. 15
- "President's Address to the Alpha Chapter of the Sigma Xi" by George F. Atkinson, Ph.B., June, 1901; 6; no. 16
- "What the New York State College of Forestry Is Doing," an open letter by the N.Y.S. College of Forestry director, B.E. Fernow, November, 1901; 6; no. 17
- Public notice for "The Sage Chapel Organ Recitals", c. 1900; 6; no. 18
- Directory for the "Cornell Alumnae Club" with members' names and addresses, 1902; 6; no. 19
- "Prospectus of the Cornell Alumni News Publishing Company", 1902; 6; no. 20
- "Mid-Winter Report of the Christian Association of Cornell University" with the names of the association's officers and trustees, 1902-1903; 6; no. 21
- "The Work of Cornell University for Agriculture," an address by President Schurman to the College of Agriculture, February 19th, 1902, February, 1902; 6; no. 22
- Article on "The Sage Chapel Memorial Apse" by Rev. William Elliot Griffis, L.H.D., 1902; 6; no. 23
- A final examination paper on Constitutional History in the United States by an anonymous and failing student, sent to Charles H. Hull for evaluation, 1902; 6; no. 24
- "Rules [about registration, conditions and failures, and more] for the Guidance of the Students", September, 1902; 6; no. 25
- "Report of Work Done and Plans for the Future" by the Cornell University Christian Association, June, 1902; 6; no. 26
- Summary of the report for 1901-1902 by W.C. Geer, President of the Cornell University Christian Association, 1902; 6; no. 27
- "Report of Work Done and Plans for the Future" by the Cornell University Christian Association, June, 1902; 6; no. 28
- Pamphlet with brief descriptions and statistical summaries of Argentina's industries, published with the compliments of the Argentine students at Cornell University, March, 1902; 6; no. 29
- Statement from the Cornell University Board of Trustees regarding the Ithaca Water Works Company and the typhoid fever epidemic, 1903; 6; no. 30
- Circular letter with an interview with President Schurman on the typhoid fever epidemic, February, 1903; 6; no. 31
- Circular letter with an interview with President Schurman on the typhoid fever epidemic, February, 1903; 6; no. 32
- Circular letter with a proposed program of undergraduate events and official events for commencement week, May, 1903; 6; no. 33
- Address on "Teaching and Research: Distinct and Indispensable Functions of a University," delivered by Lewis A. Stimson, M.D., LL.D., "the first of a series of addresses to be given in Stimson Hall", 1903; 6; no. 34
- "Summary of President's Report" for the Cornell University Christian Association, May, 1903; 6; no. 35
- Program for the Memorial Day Second Varsity Triangular Regatta between Harvard, University of Pennsylvania, and Cornell, May, 1903; 6; no. 36
- Circular letter on ticket and certificate purchasing for the Cornell University Thirty-Fifth Annual Commencement, 1903; 6; no. 37
- Program for a song recital featuring Mme. Lillian Blauvelt, including lyrics in German and in English translation, January, 1904; 6; no. 38
- Program for the "Services at the Re-Opening of Sage Chapel," led by Reverend Lyman Abbott, D.D., LL.D., January, 1904; 6; no. 39
- Pamphlet comprised of two editorials on "The Governor's Forest Policy," the first written to the Evening Post by R.W. Raymond and the second translated from New York Staatszeitung, 1904; 6; no. 40
- Program book for the "Second Annual Music Festival" at Cornell University, under the lead management of Department of Music director, Mr. Hollis E. Dann, 1905; 7; no. 1
- Circular advertising the tenth season (1904 to 1905) of the Pittsburgh Orchestra, 1904; 7; no. 2
- Program for a song recital featuring Mr. David Bispham, 1903; 7; no. 3
- "Outline of Work for the Second Term" for the course, "Masterpieces of Legal Argumentation," published by the Cornell University Department of Oratory, 1904; 7; no. 4
- Schedule, with regulations, of oratory debates for the course, "Oratory 3A", 1904; 7; no. 5
- Schedule of speaking exercises for the course, "Oratory 1A", 1904; 7; no. 6
- Schedule of train service via Lehigh Valley Railroad for Cornell Junior Week, Feburary 7th to 10th, 1905, 1905; 7; no. 7
- Short story titled "The Reformer" published in the literary periodical, The Red and Blue, by D.D.B., c. 1900; 7; no. 8
- The Brief of Phi Delta Phi (periodical), published by Charles H. Topping, vol. III, no. 1, with the article, "Cornell University College of Law, Roscoe Conkling, and Conkling Chapter" (pp. 49-59), by Fred B. Skinner, 1900; 7; no. 9
- "The Early Days of Cornell" by Goldwin Smith, D.C.L., 1904; 7; no. 10
- Program for the "Annual Junior Varsity Regatta" between Harvard and Cornell, May, 1904; 7; no. 11
- Program for the Princeton v. Cornell football game, with line-ups, November, 1901; 7; no. 12
- "First Report of the Board of Directors of the Cornell Co-operative Society", 1896; 7; no. 13
- Summary of the first report of the Board of Directors of the Cornell Co-operative Society intended for public distribution, c. 1896; 7; no. 14
- "Summary of Work of the Year 1903-04" by the Cornell University Christian Association, 1903-1904; 7; no. 15
- "Report of the Work for the Year 1904-05" by the Cornell University Christian Association, 1904-1905; 7; no. 16
- "Announcement of Courses in the Study of Missions for 1904-1905" in conjunction with the Cornell University Christian Association, 1904; 7; no. 17
- The fourth edition of the "Cornell Legal Directory" with the addresses and commencement years of Cornell attorneys, compiled by E.P. Allen, Counsellor at Law, Rochester, N.Y., March, 1905; 7; no. 18
- Program for the "Second Annual Banquet of the Society of Comparative Medicine of the New York State Veterinary College", February, 1905; 7; no. 19
- "Live Stock Registry Associations of the United States and Canada" published by the College of Agriculture, Cornell University, 1902; 7; no. 20
- "More Reasons Why State Money Should Not Be Appropriated This Year for an Agircultural Building at Cornell" by James R. Day, 1904; 7; no. 21
- "A Protest and Some Proposals Concerning Agricultural Education" and, specifically, the appropriation of state funds toward the construction of an Agriculture Hall at Cornell University, 1904; 7; no. 22
- Statement before the Committee on Agriculture by President Schurman on the work and promotion of the College of Agriculture at Cornell University, 1904; 7; no. 23
- Pamphlet by the "New York State Committee for the Advancement for Agricultural Education and Experiment", c. 1904; 7; no. 24
- Statement by L.H. Bailey "Concerning Certain Charges Made [by Chancellor James R. Day] against [the College of Agriculture at] Cornell University", 1904; 7; no. 25
- "Program of the Fifty-Ninth Annual Meeting of the New York State Teachers' Association", July, 1904; 7; no. 26
- "A Guide Book to Cornell University and Ithaca" written by the New York State Teachers' Association, 1904; 7; no. 27
- Invitation and program addressed to all former students to attend Commencement Week, 1905; 7; no. 28